<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on th4mjeed</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on th4mjeed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Thamjeed</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up the Community Edition of IBM LSF (Load Sharing Facility)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/setting-up-community-edition-lsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/setting-up-community-edition-lsf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to understand how LSF actually works, not just at a surface “submit job, job runs” level, but the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; mechanics. Most places that use LSF don’t document it well, and when they do, it’s written assuming you already run a production cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to build a small LSF Community Edition cluster at home and treat it like an EDA-style environment: master node, execution nodes, login-style submission, interactive jobs, X11, the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Samba as an Active Directory Domain Controller on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/setting-up-samba-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/setting-up-samba-ad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide, we walk through the process of setting up a Samba Active Directory Domain Controller. The goal is to create a fully functional AD environment with the ability to join Windows and Linux clients to the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup mirrors how Microsoft Active Directory works, but fully powered by open‑source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be using Fedora Linux to configure Samba AD, but you can use any Linux&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-the-domain-controller-system&#34;&gt;Preparing the Domain Controller System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin by configuring Fedora 43 to act as a domain controller. The hostname must reflect the fully qualified domain name of the AD server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLURM as a Compilation Farm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/slurm-as-a-compilation-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/slurm-as-a-compilation-farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; 📢 This document is based on my understanding of SLURM and is in no way a detailed guide covering every single topic. Take this as a practical guide from a noob’s perspective diving into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is designed to help you effectively use the SLURM scheduler on Rocky Linux 9.5 server. The Server allows you to run computational jobs using both interactive and non-interactive modes. The goal here is to make a compilation farm, although this guide specifically focuses on compiling the Linux kernel, one should note that this may also be used to compile any other tool given that the prerequisites and dependencies are known.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
